<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>data on Gustav Markkula&#39;s online resources</title>
    <link>https://gmarkkula.github.io/tags/data/</link>
    <description>Gustav Markkula&#39;s online resources (data)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
    <atom:link href="https://gmarkkula.github.io/tags/data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Dataset: Limits of human detection of visually looming collision threats</title>
      <link>https://gmarkkula.github.io/posts/2021-looming-detection-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gmarkkula.github.io/posts/2021-looming-detection-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Link: &lt;a href=&#34;https://osf.io/ku3h4&#34;&gt;https://osf.io/ku3h4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data from the experiment described in (&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pcbi.1009096&#34;&gt;Markkula et al., 2021&lt;/a&gt;), measuring human detection limits for visually looming (optically expanding) collision threats, as a function of collision threat kinematics. Participants watched a visual representation of the back of a car on a computer screen, and were instructed to respond with a button press as soon as they saw the car &amp;ldquo;coming closer&amp;rdquo;, i.e., growing on the screen. The dataset includes both behavioural responses (the button presses) as well as concurrently recorded 1024 Hz EEG data from a 64 electrode 10-20 international cap BioSemi system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further documentation of the dataset is available at the OSF link above, where there is also a link to the Github repository providing the MATLAB analysis code that was used for the analyses in (&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pcbi.1009096&#34;&gt;Markkula et al., 2021&lt;/a&gt;), as well as code for the models mentioned &lt;a href=&#34;https://gmarkkula.github.io/posts/2021-looming-detection-model/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markkula, G., Uludağ, Z., Wilkie, R. M., &amp;amp; Billington, J. (2021). Accumulation of continuously time-varying sensory evidence constrains neural and behavioral responses in human collision threat detection. PLoS Computational Biology, 17(7), e1009096. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pcbi.1009096&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pcbi.1009096&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dataset: Driver control in real and simulated low-friction vehicle testing manoeuvres</title>
      <link>https://gmarkkula.github.io/posts/2019-virtual-sweden-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gmarkkula.github.io/posts/2019-virtual-sweden-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Link: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.17605/OSF.IO/VA5KR&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.17605/OSF.IO/VA5KR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data collected with professional Jaguar Land Rover test drivers in three different low-friction vehicle testing manoeuvres, both in a real vehicle on a frozen lake, and in a high-fidelity reconstruction of the same tests in the University of Leeds moving-base driving simulator. Described and analysed in (&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1109/THMS.2018.2848998&#34;&gt;Markkula et al., 2018&lt;/a&gt;) and (&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.trf.2019.07.001&#34;&gt;Romano et al., 2019&lt;/a&gt;). The simulator data for one of the tests is also available in the dataset linked &lt;a href=&#34;https://gmarkkula.github.io/posts/2018-biolcyb-data/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markkula, G., Romano, R., Jamson, A. H., Pariota, L., Bean, A., &amp;amp; Boer, E. R. (2018). Using driver control models to understand and evaluate behavioral validity of driving simulators. &lt;em&gt;IEEE Transactions on Human-Machine Systems&lt;/em&gt;, 48(6), 592–603. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1109/THMS.2018.2848998&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1109/THMS.2018.2848998&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romano, R., Markkula, G., Boer, E., Jamson, H., Bean, A., Tomlinson, A., Horrobin, A., &amp;amp; Sadraei, E. (2019). An objective assessment of the utility of a driving simulator for low mu testing. &lt;em&gt;Transportation Research Part F: Traffic Psychology and Behaviour&lt;/em&gt;, 65, 34–45. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.trf.2019.07.001&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.trf.2019.07.001&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dataset: Human steering control in straight lane-keeping and at-limit steering tasks</title>
      <link>https://gmarkkula.github.io/posts/2018-biolcyb-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gmarkkula.github.io/posts/2018-biolcyb-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Link: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.17605/OSF.IO/DF9PW&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.17605/OSF.IO/DF9PW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data from two experiments in the University of Leeds moving-base car driving simulator, as described in (&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s00422-017-0743-9&#34;&gt;Markkula et al., 2018&lt;/a&gt;): (1) simple lane-keeping on a straight road, (2) at-limit vehicle control on a circular curve track on ice. The latter data is also included in the dataset linked &lt;a href=&#34;https://gmarkkula.github.io/posts/2019-virtual-sweden-data/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markkula, G., Boer, E., Romano, R., &amp;amp; Merat, N. (2018). Sustained sensorimotor control as intermittent decisions about prediction errors: Computational framework and application to ground vehicle steering. &lt;em&gt;Biological Cybernetics&lt;/em&gt;, 112(3), 181–207. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s00422-017-0743-9&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s00422-017-0743-9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>